LORRAYNE D. CRUZ ALMODÓVAR

Phone: 717.621.7977 | E-mail: lorraynecruz@gmail.com

EXPERIENCED QUALITY PROFESSIONAL

Accomplished Quality and Data professional with a distinguished background that includes developing protocols, executing multiple location experiments, collecting data, report writing, critical analysis, and team coordination. Efficient and resourceful while working both individually and as a team. Highly developed research, and communication skills as well as a strong ability to successfully multitask, apply analytical skills, and utilize and acquire resources.

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Master of Science in Data Science, Eastern University, Pennsylvania Master of Science in Biochemistry, University of Puerto Rico, Medical Science Campus, Puerto Rico Bachelor of Science in Applied Microbiology, Universidad del Este, Puerto Rico

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Thermo Fisher Scientific, Greenville, NC Deviations Investigator

September 2022 - Current

- Used Excel Power Query and Power BI to automate weekly Trackwise deviation data, decreasing reporting time by 25%.
- Actively collaborated and reported the analysis of the Deviation Metrics and Monitoring plan for the Greenville (GRC) site using MS Power BI and Excel.
- Effectively communicated complex data analysis to senior leadership, facilitating informed decision-making and driving organizational improvements
- Delivered regular reports summarizing data, results, and conclusions from ongoing deviation trend analysis using Power BI dashboards
- Used SQL, Python, Excel, and Power BI to convert 'Crawley Bucket' deviation classifications to the new Global Trackwise Error Classifications
- Participated in the Right First Time (RFT) Initiative and helped reduce Overdue deviations by 50% within 1 month of program initiation
- Contributed to the creation of the SmartSheet GRC deviation template and served as a Deviations Subject Matter Expert (SME)

Contract Quality Assurance Consultant - Investigations Specialist

March 2022 - September 2022

- Conducted thorough, timely, and structured investigations and product complaints for various business units (Steriles North and South, PDS, Warehouse, and Laboratories).
- Proficiently used TapRoot, 6M/Fishbone, and 5 Whys in conjunction with effective interview skills to reach true root causes.
- Independently lead Discovery and Root Cause Analysis meetings cross-functionally with Commercial and Operational teams as part of the investigation process.
- Proficient in developing comprehensive investigation plans that encompass project scope, objectives, timelines, resource allocation, and risk assessments

Pfizer, Inc., McPherson, KS Contract Quality Assurance Consultant

August 2021 - March 2022

- Provided GMP manufacturing support for Compounding, Aseptic lines, Visual Inspection, and Packing lines
- Performed Batch record review as well as event documentation for regulatory filings
- Reviewed and release materials for manufacturing activities for the COVID-19 vaccine

LORRAYNE D. CRUZ ALMODÓVAR-PAGE TWO

Phone: 717.621.7977 | E-Mail: Lorraynecruz@gmail.com

 Proactively initiated investigations and CAPA's in TrackWise for deviations occurring on the manufacturing line

Merck & Co., West Point, PA Contract Vaccine Biological Critical Regents (BCR) Specialist

June 2020 - July 2021

- Utilized statistical analysis with JMP-SAS and Excel software to create predictive models and reports for BCR life cycle reports, certifications, and qualification testing.
- Created Change Controls utilizing Trackwise software, and sample and inventory management utilizing SAP.

EUROFINS LANCASTER LABORATORIES, INC., Lancaster, PA Quality Assurance/ Data Review Scientist Team Leader

August 2014 - June 2020

- Performed reviews of scientific data, including, but not limited to standard preparations, calibrations, sample data, statistical analysis, method transfers, and other subjective review based on testing.
- Tracked, analyzed, and interpreted trends for the Biochemistry Department data using Excel and Power BI to provide relevant conclusions and recommendations to management.
- Designed and implemented automated Excel spreadsheets, reducing daily report writing time for analysts by 2 hours, ensuring consistency across the Biochemistry and Analytical Method Development teams, decreasing data integrity errors by 75%.
- Utilized JMP-SAS and Excel to implement and deploy models using predictive analytics to forecast outcome
- Used Excel to identify patterns, trends, and anomalies, providing actionable recommendations to the Stability Management Group
- Recruited and managed a Full-Time Equivalent (FTE) team of 7 scientists, creating work groups and assigning responsibilities to maximize the performance of all team members.
- Managed the budget of the Biochemistry Department client FTE by analyzing contractor expenses, cash flow statements and making decisions to maximize the effectiveness of the FTE team.
- Spearheaded the successful initiative to introduce iPads in Biochemistry and Analytical Method Development laboratories, enabling real-time access to SOPs, which led to a significant reduction in using outdated SOP versions, improved compliance and operational efficiency, and a notable reduction in paper waste.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- PPI Business System Change Champion Certification Completed on July 2023
- Lean Six Sigma Black Belt Certification (in progress) at Thermo Fisher Scientific
- Power BI Data Analyst Certification (in progress)
- Gene.AI Ambassador for Thermo Fisher Scientific

LANGUAGES

Fluent: English and Spanish